welcome back to the AI Daily Brief every
day it feels like a million new cool AI
startups launch so much so that it's
actually pretty rare that we dig deep
and cover brand new companies on this
show and yet over the past couple of
days I've seen a handful of companies
that are on the one hand just very
impressive and interesting and seemingly
high potential and additionally really
reflect and tell the story of key trends
shaping AI right now so what we're going
to do today is look at these five or so
new companies all of which have been
announced literally over the last 48
hours or so talk about them or their new
products that have been announced but
then also put them in the larger context
first up we have General Agents ceo
Sergio Ojair formerly of Tesla and
Google DeepMind writes "Today I'm
launching my new company General Agents
and our first product introducing Ace
the first real-time computer autopilot
ace is not a chatbot ace performs tasks
for you on your computer using your
mouse and keyboard at superhuman speeds
now by the way this is a show that's
going to be much better if you watch it
because there's lots of examples going
on you should be able to watch it in the
Spotify app or on YouTube but Sherjo
goes on Ace can use all the tools on
your computer and the video shared shows
it grabbing images dropping them into
Google Drive and generally doing the
types of things that a human would do
their preview videos also show the
method of interaction in Premiere Pro it
shows a user using the Ace bar to for
example slow the video clip down to 50%
split the clip once with the cut tool
and then export it and again you're
using verbal instructions and then
letting ACE actually do the work they
point out that this can be really
helpful not just for increasing your
speed and efficiency but also for tools
that you're still learning how to use
there's a bunch of other things about
ACE as well but the big thing that
they're hammering is that it's fast in
fact they claim 20 times faster than
competing agents making it as they say
more practical for everyday use speed is
definitely what caught people's
attention with this replet CEO Amjad
Msad said "Insane speed computer use
models have not seen major commercial
breakthrough because they're slow and
expensive this is a huge unlock."
William Gus a former research scientist
at OpenAI who's now a general agent as
well writes "Ace is the world's fastest
AI computer use agent this is
fundamentally a new way to use computers
when someone asked "How does it work?"
William responded "It takes in pixels
and instructions and outputs click drag
keyboard etc actions at 300 milliseconds
roundtrip latency." In other words it's
doing full screenshot image processing
extremely quickly now in terms of the
discussion around this outside of it
just being fast some people pointed out
that advances coming from startups like
this mean that it's not just the big
labs that are going to have all the fun
in the new era f schuman on Twitter also
pointed out that the expansion of human
creativity to go with a theme from
yesterday's show is one of the
byproducts of this type of computer use
tool where as he puts it anyone can now
operate software without even knowing
how to operate it that is a huge
breakthrough and certainly wasn't on my
bingo card for this year so there are
obviously a lot of themes that I think
this startup represents broadly speaking
of course agents the most important most
dominant category of AI advancements
right now but more specifically this
idea of expanding agent capabilities
through computer use this is something
that we started to see inklings of at
the end of last year and this appears to
be a major jump forward on that
obviously if you listen to yesterday's
show about the five fastchanging AI
transformations that'll keep you up at
night you'll have heard me talk about
the expansion of human creativity and as
we just heard being able to talk at
software and have your agent do it with
you does absolutely expand which
software tools a person can use lastly
the fact that the speed of computer use
is now exceeding humans I think gives us
a glimpse into the future where AI and
agents aren't just as performant as
people but are actually better at things
now obviously AI is better at many
things already but this is a highly
visual example of that another theme
which it's a little too early to explore
is whether US state-of-the-art agent
capabilities can drive as much virality
as recent releases from China like Manis
we might be a little constrained in this
case because general agents is only
available as a research preview not as a
full product but still that's something
that I'll be watching next up we have
Lindy and of course while Lindy isn't
new its new swarms feature is i won't
spend a ton of time on this because I
got into it yesterday but I think
co-founder Lindy Drop actually does a
great job explaining this she writes
"This AI agent turns one workflow into a
multi- aent empire working in parallel
fed it one event URL and here's what
happened it extracted every speaker's
details deep researched each person
using LinkedIn news and PR found and
transcribed their podcast appearances
crafted emails with their exact quotes
making them impossible to ignore
identified lookalike profiles and
repeated the process on autopilot the
net result she says it just sent 370
impossible to ignore personalized emails
in seconds versus an entire day of
manual work we're building AI employees
that run entire companies autonomously
what about someone outside the company
michael Raspusi writes "First test using
Lindy Loops trying out a series of
custom deep research agents using
Perplexity and Anthropic context: We're
prepping for our next AI and health hack
so I want a quick update across
different non-invasive imaging
modalities i texted at LFUS FNIRS and
ultrasound and it cooked what would have
taken 1 to two hours manually 25 minutes
with AI tools took 2 minutes with Lindy
AI one more test from Alex Carson they
write "Agent swarms let AI agents
duplicate themselves to tackle hundreds
of tasks simultaneously the new
capability immediately scales what's
possible with AI automation by allowing
agents to divide and conquer across
large data sets without complex coding
or custom API connections you provide a
list of tasks and Lindy automatically
spawns duplicate agents to handle each
item concurrently
testing this feature with a YouTube to
blog post workflow showed the impressive
potential i created a simple flow that
triggers when new URLs are added to a
spreadsheet creates a loop that
processes each URL simultaneously
transcribes each video and generates a
professionally formatted blog post and
then returns all completed posts and
chat messages and so what's the theme
here it's not just agents obviously
we've already covered agents as the big
dominant theme no what's interesting to
me is this is effectively my Doctor
Strange theory of AI agent work come to
life this is not a onetoone replacement
for existing work this is the very early
innings of what you can do if you were
able to hire hundreds of people instead
of just one for a particular task those
370 personalized emails that Lindy sent
is an example of how you would apply
this to sales i think we are going to
see so much more of this in the next few
months and it's actually going to take
the new capabilities being available
before people can even come close to
figuring out how to actually take full
advantage
startup number three is called Paid and
a very appropriate name it is manny
Medina writes "I'm officially launching
my new company Paid we just raised€ 10
million euro to solve the biggest
problem no one's talking about in AI ai
agents are growing fast but face a
critical challenge how to monetize and
capture the value they create
traditional software billing doesn't
solve this problem at Paid we're solving
this problem by smart pricing that
aligns with actual value creation
real-time margin tracking to ensure
profitability clear dashboards that
demonstrate ROI to customers billing
invoicing revenue recovery taxes and all
the back office needs in a single pane
of glass with just a few lines of codes
AI builders can focus on creating
amazing agents while we handle the
business engine behind them summing it
up even more clearly their website calls
this the business engine for AI agents
to me this is reflective of the fact
that agents are now officially shifting
from interesting toys and novelties to
actual productionready tools that are
going to go in and change how we do work
paid is an example of the critical
infrastructure that is being built to
enable agents to live up to their full
potential effectively everything that
human employees do now every service
that we have around them is going to
have some proximate version in the agent
world this is going to be an incredibly
rich vein for startups in the coming
years and as you can see is already
happening with Gusto right now next up
we're moving on from agents at least
sort of to another huge theme of the
moment which is of course vibe coding
and for that we turn to the company
called yes vibe code they write in order
for billions of people to vibe code we
need a tool with the power of cursor and
the simplicity of chat GBT that they
argue is the new app that they've built
vibe code now this comes from Riley
Brown and his co-founders riley was and
is I think the world's biggest AI Tik
Tocker but over the past six months or
so has really gone allin on vibe coding
he's been building things for himself
using content to come up with new
theories of how creators are going to
code things in the future and this is
the app that he and some friends
basically built for himself to do what
he wanted to do one of the examples he
showed off was vibe coding a mobile
video game in a single prompt and what's
cool about this if you've used something
like Lovable and Bolt is that this is a
native mobile interface instead of
focusing on web applications Vive Code
is starting with a focus on mobile
applications and when excited users
started posting on the announcement
thread that signup wasn't working Vive
Code basically said that they were
already full up so in terms of the
themes here obviously Vive coding in
general is a big one but the mobile
integration is really fascinating as
well as Eddie Yun points out right now
the average interaction with vibe coding
is still via text but imagine vibe
coding with voice funny enough when
Andre Karpathy originally talked about
vibe coding he talked about how he was
using whisper to talk to his computer to
do it so in some ways this would be an
actual instantiation of where the whole
thing started vibe codeandanda writes
"The best feeling in the world is when
you build something and others can use
it with vibe code we hope to enable
anyone get that feeling." And of course
that is the big resonance of vibe coding
with people is this expansion of human
creativity and creative capacity and
that was not the only example one of the
challenges for vibe coders is that there
are a whole bunch of pieces beyond just
writing the code and some of those
things remain outside of people's
technical capacities now of course you
can use vibe coding tools or separate
LLMs to get help with those things and
all of the vibe coding tools have some
version of a single button push to
publish still Andre Carpathy summed up a
lot of people's feelings when he tweeted
about a week ago "The reality of
building web apps in 2025 is that it's a
bit like assembling IKEA furniture
there's no full stack product with
batteries included you have to piece
together and configure many individual
services front end and back end hosting
database authentication blob storage
email payments background jobs analytics
monitoring dev tools secrets etc he
continues i'm relatively new to modern
webdev and find the above a bit
overwhelming eg i'm embarrassed to share
it took me 3 hours the other day to
create and configure a superbase with a
Versell app and resolve a few errors the
second you stray just slightly from the
getting started tutorial in the docs
you're suddenly in the wilderness it's
not even code it's configurations
plumbing orchestration workflows best
practices a lot of glory will go to
whoever figures out how to make it
accessible and just work out of the box
for both humans and increasingly and
especially AIs now a lot of the vibe
coding platforms showed up in the
comments saying "Keep an eye out." Anton
from Lovable said "Exactly what we're
building at Lovable." One of the
respondents though was Nicholas Charier
who wrote "This is exactly our vision
for Mocha not glued together developer
tools all made slightly easier but a
fully integrated one-stop shop." And
this company Mocha was also just
announced a couple of days ago nicholas
writes "Introducing Mocha we're
incredibly excited to launch the
absolute best way to build full stack
web apps no code no templates just
describe what you want and watch it come
to life he continues "For too long ideas
have died because building products
require too much technical knowledge
we're changing this describe your vision
in human terms get a complete working
product in minutes keep ittering and
adding features then deploy in one click
all integrated unlike other website
builders Mocha aims to be fully
integrated you won't need to pay and
connect five services to get off
databases front-end hosting email etc
just one we take a highly opinionated
approach based on our experience
building top web products like Pinterest
and Next Door you describe outcomes
Mocha handles the rest they even gave an
example of what you could do nicholas
calls out Tom a small business owner in
Texas who operates an HVAC servicing
company tom used Mocha to build
customtailored web apps for each
customer with personalized branding and
functionality which he said increased
deal conversion customer satisfaction
and velocity by 200% and indeed he sums
up our theme here at the end we're
entering an era where everyone not just
engineers can build personal software
the era of idea people and personal
software we couldn't be more excited now
I haven't had a chance to dig into Mocha
yet but in terms of us looking at
startups both as very cool things on
their own but also as reflective of
trends it is so clear that this is where
vibe coding is heading this is
absolutely the next frontier the thing
for people who are trying to push things
beyond just prototyping and into
production i think it is no mean feat to
actually integrate this entire
experience end to end but I also think
that this is going to be completely
table stakes for these companies it is
going to be an absolute onslaught race
between Bolt and Lovable and Mocha and
the big beneficiary is all of us who get
to build things that were never possible
before so that is the list five startups
that have come out in the past week that
reflect some of AI's most important
trends again we had General Agents who
released ACE the real-time computer
autopilot lindy who announced their
agent swarms basically if you ever
wanted your own army of employees now
you can have it paid which is building
agent infrastructure making it easier
for agents to actually interact with
financial rails vibe Code which is
taking the vibe coding world onto mobile
and Mocha which is advancing vibe coding
entirely by moving towards an endto-end
experience ai remains the most
interesting and exciting space in the
world and I'm thrilled to be able to
share it with you every day for now
that's going to do it for today's AI
daily brief appreciate you listening or
watching as always and until next time
peace